

Joshua Jainga

253-347-8441 jjainga@gmail.com Sammamish, WA 98075

WEBSITES

PORTFILE.HEROKU.COM linkedin.com/in/joshuajainga github.com/jjainga

SUMMARY

Brand Statement Full Stack Developer leveraging economics and operations management background to help solve complex problems to improve user experience. Quick to learn, integrate and teach new knowledge to benefit the team I am supporting. I am excited to continue to grow my skills to build a better experience for everyone.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS
- Javascript
- Node.js
- MySQL
- Sequelize
- Express.js
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- React jQuery
- Python
- VBA
- RESTful API
- Strategic planning
- Knowledge of performance tracking

- Outstanding communication skills
- Customer and vendor relations
- Supervisory role background
- Ability to write reports
- Safety protocol
- Staff supervision
- Employee development
- Schedule management
- Supervision and training
- Purchasing and planning
- Sound judgment
- Performance improvements
- Cost analysis and savings
- Cross-functional team management

EXPERIENCE

Operations Area Manager II

Fulfillment Center Feb 2019 to Current

- Assist in the development of new area managers/process assistants in the outbound department. Leads department meetings amongst peers to discuss weekly changes and metrics
- Creates learning curve performance calculator with VBA to identify areas of
 opportunity per associate in the chuting/pack department by showing percent to
 labor plan, week-over-week performance, trend for current shift. information is
 used to help with targeting performance coaching for department managers.
- Creates hourly shift tracker with VBA to assist in the ad hoc reporting of all
 outbound department's metrics. Information is used to identify opportunities in
 current labor plan and show relative performance in day-over-day and week-overweek.
- Leading 30-60 people to deliver 200,000 units daily at 95-105% to labor plan.
- Create purchase order requisitions for materials to better associates work life.
- Safety Leadership Index of 6% unfavorable against the network average of 13% unfavorable.
- Track quarterly shift metrics to proactively identify areas of opportunity to meet volume and through-put-hour shift goals.

- Cross-functional collaboration to ensure customer's order deadlines and critical pool times are met.
- Create ad hoc reporting tools to identify productivity opportunities (performance levels of 80% or below) to drive proactive coaching. Daily coaching to individuals that drive 5-10% increase in performance.
- Determine team productivity needs and work with other Area Managers to balance shift labor needs.
- Develop Associates to assist in their promotional and career goals.
- Assure that Associate compliance and consistency is maintained, and that corrective action is taken when needed.
- Supported regional branches with turnaround management processes, increasing organization and efficiency to enhance profitability.
- Recruited and trained tier 1 and 3 employees to enable adherence to common standards and procedures.
- Verified adherence to OSHA and internal safety standards to minimize risks and enhance workplace safety.
- Educated employees on corporate policy and procedure compliance to facilitate improved operations outcomes.

Seasonal Procurement Operations Analyst

Kent, WA

Amazon BFI4/ Aug 2018 to Feb 2019

- Create reports analyzing trends of spending per blanket purchase order to evaluate potential cost savings and present to Sr. Ops.
- •Initiate and lead cost saving project in collaboration with Sr. Ops and finance team, which saves \$120K annually.
- Take part in discussions with Sr. Ops on barriers for Associates and provide support with solutions.
- Build and manage vendor relationships, negotiate/facilitate vendor proposal for site projects.
- Deep Dive in data of vendor spending history to determine future budgets.
- Approve Coupa web requests with a 24-hour deadline.
- Track account payable holds to find the root cause of issues and execute resolutions.
- Resolve a standard of 80% account payable holds on a weekly basis (six weeks of 100% resolution).
- Facilitate communication between supporting vendors and Amazon to provide a safe, clean, and efficient work facility.
- Developed innovative financial controls system to optimize accounting processes.
- Analyzed operational performance to identify pain points and provided actionable solutions to management.
- Applied skills in Excel to create data models and trend forecasts.

Non-Inventory Receiver

Kent, WA

Amazon BFI4/ Nov 2017 to May 2018

• Develop an unloading process which increases productivity by 20% per unload,

- resulting in the potential for an additional 365 unloads per year.
- Receive and verify purchases through Coupa and disperse non-inventory items to appropriate departments.
- Maintain consistent workflow throughout the building by prioritizing standard work against the needs of other departments.
- Certified in power industrial trucks, vertical reciprocating conveyor, and trailer dock and release.
- Identify and solve problems with the sorting process to ensure the highest quality possible; kept defects below 1%.
- Operated lift and hand trucks to transfer materials to and from target areas.
- Compared shipment contents with paperwork to support inventory accuracy and records management.
- Performed inspections of shipment contents, verifying accuracy against invoices and manifests.
- Implemented cost-effective methods, carriers and routes to optimize shipping and receiving strategies.
- Liaised with vendor representatives to rectify damages and shortages.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Full Stack Development: Full Stack Development

University Of Washington Nov 2020

Seattle, WA

Bachelor of Science: Economics

Eastern Washington University Jul 2015

Cheney, WA

- Honors Recognition International Economic Society Study Abroad Global City Hong Kong
- Minor in Decision Science

Associate of Arts: Direct Transfer

Bellevue College Jul 2012

Bellevue, WA